

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Project Lead seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, ASP. Net MVC, SQL

Server, JavaScript, Angularjs, jQuery, JIRA, HTML, SVN, AWS, CSS, Git

Current Designation: Project Lead / Operations Head Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: Kaira Software Pvt. Ltd Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Current Location: Ahmedabad

Pref. Location: Ahmedabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Project Mar-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Project Lead/Manager, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, ASP. Net MVC, SQL

Server, JavaScript, Angularjs, jQuery, JIRA, HTML, SVN, AWS, CSS, Git

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Having 10+ years of experience in IT industry, with knowledge of full software development life cycle from gathering user requirements to deployment on production.

As a Project Lead delivered projects mainly based on Microsoft Technologies C#, ASP.NET, .NET Core. Apart from this also handle a few projects related to open source frameworks like Laravel, Code Igniter, WordPress and Shopify. Familiar with several technical tools, APIs and services for Marketing, Automation, Analytics, Data Mining, Geocoding, CRMs, Payment Gateways, free and paid resources for design, ready code libraries, SEO, Social Media APIs, APM like Stackify and Sentry which while ancillary to the project are important for success and completion of the project.

Work Experience

Kaira Software Pvt. Ltd as Project Lead / Operations Head Jan 2014 to Till Date

Project: More Customers App Role Performed : Project Lead Duration: Mar 2017 - Till Date

Team Size: 10

Project Description: This is Kaira's inhouse product. With a vision to allow anyone to create their eCommerce website under 5 minutes. Once the user signup, he gets his website with banners and COD enabled. With very simple configuration steps a user can integrate payment gateways like Instamojo, RazorPay, Paypal and Stripe. User can enable 3rd party scripts like Google Analytics, Facebook Pixel, Tawk.to, Facebook messager etc.

More Customers App can create a full-fledged eCommerce website with features like Faceted Search, Variant

Management, Taxation, delivery charge configuration in 5 different modes

User can add his own domain with simple CNAVE configuration and site is automatically enabled with Cloudflare proxy and storing images on S3 for better performance

User can manage his website via Admin panel, Android App and iOS App. On top of it, he can avail his own branded mobile app like Myntra.

In the last 2 years, More Customers App has grown to 300+ clients with Indian and international. More Customers App has 25K+ android app downloads.

Handled the team which comprises 6+ web developers, 2 iOS developers and 2 Android developers along with 2 QA At initial stage worked with a designer to create the mockups of Mobile App and front eCommerce site.

Design the Database along with senior developers

Implemented the Agile methodologies to make features live on a weekly basis. In case of bug or issues to give build immediately

Daily stand up meetings and reporting of Sprints to the director.

Communicating with the marketing team to resolve the end client queries.

Setup the process for posting a bug or features request for the client.

Configure the Cloudflare as proxy server and single panel to manage the DNS of all paid client domains.

Closely worked with developers to resolve the issues and improve the performance of the application.

In recent time done the competitors analysis to list the features which are missing in More Customers App.

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Learnt and implemented SEO technique which helps to rank the site better. Learnt the Best practices of On-Page SEO,

Meta Tags and Schema Markup.

Environment: C#, ASP.NET M/C, PetaPoco, MS SQL, AngularJs, Bootstrap, CSS3, Windows Services, Redis

Cache, AWS EC2, S3 Buckets, Cloudflare, iOS App, Android App Project: The Design Bridge

Role Performed: Project Lead Duration: Feb 2019 - Oct 2019

Team Size: 8

Project Description: This is Kaira's other inhouse product. The project aims to create a bridge between Builders,

Architects, Manufacturer, Dealer and End User who are looking for the same to build home/office.

This is the first .NET Core project which is deployed on Linux with MySQL as database.

Role & Responsibilities:

Handled the team which comprises 4 web developers, 2 iOS developers and 2 Android developers along with 1 QA Coordinating with marketing team which is operating from Jaipur.

Understanding the requirement from the marketing team and envision how it can be implemented in the website,

Android and iOS app.

Implemented Elastic Search to provide a speedy search for materials of various brands

One of the critical requirement was to provide a way to the marketing team to upload 2K to 3K products daily. For this developed google sheets based macro by which by just entering data in excel it will push to live DB and for images upload the folder via FTP.

Environment: C#, .NET Core 2.1, PetaPoco, MySQL, AngularJs, Bootstrap, CSS3, Digital Ocean Droplet, S3 Buckets,

Synoverge Technologies Pvt. Ltd as Software Developer

Jun 2012 to Dec 2013

At Synoverge worked on 2 projects as a software developer. An ongoing project which was for HDFC insurance unit for which worked on an assigned module.

For JCl project worked on Salesforce integration and few other modules. The was related to providing cost estimation for the maintenance work.

Kaira Software Pvt. Ltd. as Software Developer

Nov 2009 to Apr 2012

Worked on few projects which were mainly on the education domain. Kiwi project was developed for the private institutes to manage teacher and students.

Similarly, Classmate project was mainly developed for schools in Europe to make the schedule of a teacher, manage the onboarding of students and other activities like tracking the fees, exam etc.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Computers) from Government Engineering Colleg, Sector-28, Gandhinagar, Gujarat University in 2009

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
C#, ASP.Net MVC, PetaPoco, IoC,		
Window Services, RESTful APIs		
.NET CORE 2.1 - 3.1, .NET Framework		
SQL SERVER, MySQL, Redis Cache		
Angularjs, Jquery, Javascript, HTML, CSS		
Visual Studio, SQL Server, GIT, TFS		
AWS EC2,S3,Elastic Search, DNS		
Redmine, Trello, JIRA, MS Project		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Gujarati				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary
Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved @ 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.